Larry Bogart Papers 2012.0088
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series I: Inventory, undated, 1958-2001
  - Correspondence, publications, books, maps, posters, manuscripts, 1957, 1967-1969, 1974-1982, 1984, 1988-1989, 1990; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 13)
    Articles and Publications: Book "A Citizen's Guide to Nuclear Power" by Ralph E. Lapp; Periodical "People & Energy" (May, 1975); Manuscript "Creating Multimedia Shows on the Scandinavian Nations: A Multimillenial Saga" by Walter E. Tengelsen; Publication "Nuclear Facts" from Duchess County Environmental Association, Nuclear Moratorium Coalition (1974); Publication "The President's Environmental Program, 1977;" "Public Power Weekly Newsletter;" Publication "The Northern Sun News;" Report on "Theoretical Possibilities and Consequences of Major Accidents in Large Nuclear Power Plants" (1957); Publication "The Energy Consumer" (1979); "The Nuclear Free Press" newsletter; "Scientific American" (1982); Publication "Power Surge: The Statos and Near-Term Potential of Renewable Energy Technologies" By Nancy Rader et al, 1989; Sequential art (comic) publication "Auntie Nuke's Guide to Nuclear Power" by Pete Sinclair (1979); Publication "Nucleonics Week" (1980).
    Organizations: Friends of the Hudson; U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission; Woodstock Nuclear Opponents; Citizens Energy Council; Citizens' Energy Project.
    Nuclear Plants: Sterling Nuclear Plant (New York); Three Mile Island; Indian Point.
    Other Items: Map/poster titled "The Nuclear Weapons Complex Transportation Routes" (1988).
    Other Topics: Attempted Shutdown of Indian Point; Threat of aging nuclear reactors; Petition against Indian Point (partially granted); Solar power; Reviews of film 'The China Syndrome;" Anti-vivisection; Nuclear war and climate change; Balloon launch at Indian Point (1980); Disposal of radioactive waste.]
  - Clippings, publications, fliers, correspondence, books, 1941-1942, 1954, 1967-1974, 1976-1980, 1982, 1985-1990; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 14)
    Articles and Publications: "Environmentalists for Full Employment" newsletter (1980); U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission report on "Safety Aspects of Industrial Radiography for State Regulatory Personnel" (1980); Publication "IAEA Nuclear Science Publications Catalogue 1970;" Publication "Science" (periodical, 1977); Article "Larry Bogart's Change of Heart" by John LeFever; Article "A Second Coal Age Promises to Slow our Dependence on Imported Oil" by David Sheridan (Smithsonian, Aug. 1977); Publication "The New Castle Gazette" (1974); Article "The Policy of Below Regulatory Concern" by Sara Shannon; flier "Coming Soon! Radioactive Waste;" Publication "Groundswell" from the Nuclear Information and Resource Service; Book "Final Siting Criteria Report for the New Jersey Low-Level Radioactive Waste Facility Siting Project" (1990); "Nuclear Opponents" Newsletter (issues from 1978-1979; also titled "People and Power," and "Watch on the AEC"); Publication "On the Planet Earth, Sept. 1969, The Unanimous Declaration of Interdependence;" Booklet "Nuclear Energy: Promise at Dawn?" by Dr. George L. Weil; Publication "Main Currents in Modern Thought" (issues from 1941-1942).
    Organizations: Women Strike for Peace, Nuclear Waste Committee; Community for Creative Non-Violence; Nuclear Information and Resource Service.
    Nuclear Plants: North Carolina Cliffside reactor (Duke Power Co.); Davis-Besse Nuclear Reactor (Ohio); Seabrook.
    Other Items: Fliers on Radalert device; Larry Bogart's Resume (1969).
    Other Topics: Davis-Besse Nuclear Reactor hearing, 1970; Solar and coal energy; Lawsuits related to Three Mile Island accident.]
  - Clippings, notes, correspondence, publications, fliers, galley proofs, transcripts, 1962, 1966-1967, 1969-1970, 1972-1974, 1978, 1980-1982; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 15)
    Articles and Publications: Article "The Case against Space Weapons" by Dr. Robert M. Bowman; periodical "Vita News: A Special Energy Issue" (July 1981); Manuscript of report "Wind Energy: Another Form of Solar Energy" from the League Against Nuclear Dangers Committee for Nuclear Responsibility; publication "Eastwest Journal" (1980); publication "Women and Life on Earth Tidings 'Earthwatch'"; Sierra Club flier "They've been Defying the Law for Years;" publication "World Peace News" (1981); Publication "Disarming Notes;" Publication "Watch on the AEC" (1973); issues of "Anti-Pollution League Bulletin;" Publication "The Crab Sheet: News of the Safe Energy Movement from Chesapeake Energy Alliance" (1981); Publication "Nuclear Explosives in Peacetime: A Scientists' Institute for Public Information Workbook;" Flier on "MHD (Magnetohydrodynamics) Power Generation" from the Safe Energy Alternatives Alliance; Article "How to Convert a Plutonium-Powered Heart Pacemaker into a Terrorism Weapon Capable of Making up to Two Square Miles of any City Uninhabitable;" U.S. Atomic Energy Commission Report "Quantitative Results of Accident Sequences" (1974); Galley proof of article "The Myth of Safe Nuclear Power Plants" by E.R. Hogman; Manuscript and drafts for article "Those Marvelous Plastics" by Bob Pointer; Article "Unedited Transcript of Remarks of Dr. John W. Gofman, University of California" (1970).
    Organizations: World Constitution and Parliament Association; The Solar Lobby; Greenpeace; Save New England (Larry Bogart, director); Environmental Coalition on Nuclear Power; International Cooperation Institute; Friends of the Hudson; Safe Energy Alternatives Alliance; Anti-Pollution League; Association for the Protection of the Adirondacks.
    Nuclear Plants: Vermont Yankee; Indian Point; Storm King.
    Other Topics: Infant Mortality after Three Mile Island; Observance of Hiroshima Day; Alternative energy. ]
  - Clippings, publications, maps, publications, correspondence, transcripts, notes, 1965, 1968-1972, 1976, 1979-1980, 1990; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 16)
    Articles and Publications: Publication "Watch on the AEC" newsletter (1970); Publication "The Village Voice" (Sept. 26, 1968); Article "Reflections on the Draft" by "A Seasoned Draft Resister" (1980); Article "Atomic Power: Who Looks After Public Safety?" by A.J. Ackerman (1969); Publication "Report from the 89th Congress, First Session" (1965); Publication "Testimony of Adolph J. Ackerman, Consulting Engineer, Madison, Wis., Appearing Before the Senate Select Committee on Atomic Energy, Commonwealth of Pennsylvania" (1970); Publication "People and Energy" (1979); Publication "Public Power Weekly" (1980); Publication "Coalition for a Non-Nuclear World;" Publication "Campaign Against Nuclear Power Newsletter" (1979); "Environment" magazine (1979); Publication "Friends of the Earth's Not Man Apart" (1976); Transcript of Larry Bogart's Statement "Before Region #1, Nuclear Regulatory Commission Workshop on Emergency Preparedness Rules" (1980); Publication "Access to Energy" newsletter (1980); Publication "The Mobilizer;" publication "Another Mother for Peace" newsletter; Publication "Environmental Action" magazine (1980); Publication "765 Hotline;" Publication "Solar Scan" Newsletter; Publication "The New Jersey Sun" (1980).
    Organizations: Independent Phi Beta Kappa Environmental Study Group; Coalition for a Non-Nuclear World; Friends of the Hudson.
    Nuclear Plants: INdian Point, Seabrook, Shoreham.
    Other Items: Map "Operable Northeast Nuclear Power Plants," with marked danger zones.
    Other topics: President Carter and Nuclear Waste; 1980 Indian Point Reopening; Nuclear Regulatory Commission licensing nuclear plants; Lawsuits against Three Mile Island.
  - Publications, clippings, manuscripts, correspondence, fliers, dummies, books, 1954, 1963-1969, 1970, 1975-1976, 1978-1979, 1981, 1989-1990, 1999, 2001; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 17)
    Articles and publications: Issues of newsletter "National Fluoridation News" (1963-1968); Article "The Invisible Threat: The Stifled Story of Electric Waves" by Susan Schiefelbein (1979); publication "Solar Energy Digest" (1981); Newsletter "Anti-Pollution League Bulletin" (1967); Publication "Local Action/Research Guide No. 1: Weapons for Counterinsurgency: Chemical/Biological, Anti-Personnel, Incendiary" (1970); Article manuscript "Nuclear Power: Is there Still a Debate?" (date and author unknown); U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission "News Releases" (1999); Publication "Women's Environmental and Development Organization (WEDO) News and Views" (1999); Publication "Forest Magazine" (1999); Publication "Nuclear Power Costs Twenty-Third Report by the Committe on Government Operations, together with Additional, Minority and Dissenting Views" (1978); Publication "Resources for the Future" (1979); Publication "Borrowed Times" (1979); Booklet "Nuclear Energy: Promises, Promises" by George L. Weil; Booklet "Ether-Technology: A Rational Approach to Gravity Control" by Rho Sigma; Publication "Free Energy: The Final Solutions!"; Boolket "Goodwill Ambassadors" (1963); Article "The LIving ORders" by Ruth Lofgren (1954); Publication "Nuclear Opponents" (1978); Flier for book "Supersonic Instruments of Knowing" by Christopher Hills; Publication "Environmental Information" (1975); Article "Biological Effects of Tritium" by Charles W. Huver (1969); Article "The Lloyd Harbon Study Group Intervention: A Response" by Ann Carl; Article "A Personal Case Against Nuclear Power" by Glenn Liming (1975).
    Organizations: Nukewatch; The Solar Lobby; Citizens Energy Council; Palmetto Alliance; Maritime Energy Coalition; Citizens Committee for Protection of the Environment.
    Nuclear Plants: Davis-Besse.
    Other Items: Dummies of "Contratom" newsletter (1990); Correspondence to Larry Bogart at the Citizens Energy Council.
    Other Topics: Radioactive waste disposal; Alternative energy; Ralph Nader; Violations at Davis-Besse plant (1975).]
  - Publications, fliers, books, 1990-1992, 1994-2000; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 18)
    Box contains only publications, including: U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission News Releases (1999-2000); "E: The Environmental Magazine" (1999); "War & Peace Digest" (1995); "The Workbook" publication from Southwest Research & Information Center (1998); "Ecofables/Ecoscience" (1998); "Groundwork" (1998); "High Ground" (1998); "WEDO News & Views" (1998); "Common Sense" (1998); "Watershed Focus" (1998); "Europe Energy" (1998) published by Europe Information Service; Fliers opposing Cassini Probe; "Nukewatch Pathfinder" (1998); Flier on "Non-Stockpile Chemical weapons Citizens Coalition;" Publication "Nuclear Reactor" from Concerned Citizens for Nuclear Safety; Book "Proposed Standard Technical Specification for Permanently Defueled Westinghouse Plants" (1998); GAO Report "Nuclear Waste: Understanding of Waste Migration at Hanford is Inadequate for key Decisions" (1990); "Time" magazine (1992); "Global Change" (1998); "The Organic Organizer" (1997); U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission Publication "Staff Responses to Frequently Asked Questions Concerning Decommisioning of Nuclear Power Reactors" (1998); "Rocky Mountain Institute Newsletter" (1997); U.S. NRC Publication "Human Performance in Radiological Survey Scanning;" "Clementine" (1994); Book "Profiles in Carbon: An Update on Population, Consumption, and Carvon Dioxide Emissions" by Robert Engelmann (1998); "Bombs Away!" newsletter (1998); Publication "Sea Grant's Guide to Coastal Science Experts" (Second Edition); U.S. NRC Publication "U.S. Nuclear Power Plant Operating Cost and Experience Summaries" (1997); Publication "Office for Analysis and Evaluation of Operational Data Annual Report 1996: Reactors" (U.S. NRC); Publication "Environmental Radiation in New York State: 1991 Annual Report;" "Space Alert" newsletter "(2000); "WESPAC NEwsletter" (1999).
  - Correspondence, clippings, fliers, publications, maps, transcripts, dummies, 1965-1966, 1968-1969, 1970-1972, 1974-1976, 1978-1980, 1983-1987, 1990-1991; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 19)
    Articles and publications: Flier on "NIRS: The Nuclear Information & Resource Service;" Flier "U.S. Is Vulnerable!: Dr. Teller's Warning;" Publication "Allendale: The Way We Were" (1974); Published Scientific papers on Radiation, including "Radiation Aging by High LET Radiation: The Implications of Assuming Cell Nucleus Irradiation is the Relevant Parameter" by Donald P. Geesaman, and papers by J.W. Gofman, including "Radiation Induction of Breast Cancer in the Rat," and "A Specific Common Chromosomal Pathway for the Origin of Human Malignancy" (1969); Publication "Groundswell" (NIRS Newsletter, 1984); Publication "The Nuclear Monitor" (NIRS, 1985); Article "Tossing Out Some Common Myths About Vegetarianism" by Alex Hershaft, PhD (1983); Publication "Earthholder" newsletter (1985); Article "Iceberg Water: An Assessment" by W.F. Weeks" (1980); Publication "Working Hand in Hand with Industry in Southern New Jersey" from the Atlantic City Electric Company (undated); Publication "Radiation Events Monitor" (1987); Publication "The Waste Paper" (The Sierra Club, 1979); U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission News Releases (1990); Book "How Safe is New Mexico's Atomic City?: Radiation Control at Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory" by Phil Niklaus and Dede Feldman; Publication "New Directions" newsletter (1980); Transcript "Three Mile Island Report: The Macneil/Lehrer Report" (1979); Publication "Saucer News: Official Publication of the Saucer and Unexplained Celestial Events Research Society" (1966); Publication "Report for the Consultation on the Air Quality Control Region for the New Jersey-New York-Connecticut Interstate Area" (1968); Issues of "Nuclear Opponents" (1975, 1978-1980), "Energy News Digest" (1985), and "Nuclear Hazards" (1986) from the Citizens Energy Council.
    Organizations: Citizens Energy Council; Council of Great Lakes Governors; Forelaws on Board; Women Strike for Peace; Church Women United; Conservation Foundation; Friends of the Hudson.
    Nuclear Plants: Storm King; Seabrook; Maine Yankee.
    Other Items: Correspondence to Larry Bogart at Energy News Digest (1985); Map "Delaware Valley Council Tentative Expressways Plan" (Jan. 1965); Preliminary dummies of "Watch on the AEC," publication of the Citizens Energy Council (1971).
    Other Topics: Dangers of Radiation; Fire at Maine Yankee (1991); Nuclear Plant Retirement; Dr. Rosalie Bertell Wins "The Right Livelihood Award" for work against nuclear power (1986).]
  - Clippings, publications, postcards, correspondence, 1962, 1965-1966, 1968-1972, 1975-1976, 1978, 1980-1982, 1989-1991; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 20)
    Articles and Publications: Publication "The Rape of San Francisco Bay: Praise the Buck and Pass the Dirt" (1968); Publication "Three Mile Island Alert Island Updates" newsletter (1980); U.S. Atomic Energy Commission publication "The Nuclear Industry-- 1968 and Beyond" by Dr. Glenn T. Seaborg; Publication "The Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists" (1980); Article "Health Effects of Low Level Radiation" by Rosalie Bertell, PhD (1975); Publication "Foghorn" newsletter (1990); Publication "The Hudson Valley Green Times" (1990); Publication "Public Power Weekly Newsletter" (1972); Publication "National Coal Policy Conference, Inc. Newsletter" (1970); Publication 'Energy News Digest," from Citizens Energy Council (1981); French Language publication "Protection Contre les Rayonnements Ionisants" (1970); Article "Radioactivity from 'Clean' Nuclear Power" by Joel A. Snow, PhD (1989); Article "Secrecy and Nuclear Power" by Thomas B. Cochran; Publication "Rad-Alert" newsletter (1990); Publication 'The Hudson: Summary Report of the Hudson River Valley Commission" (1966); Publication "A Thermal Profile of the waters of New York State" (1968); Publication, U.S. Atomic Energy Commission report, "In The Matter of Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc. (Indian Point Nuclear Generating Unit 3)" (1969); Publication "Nuclear Power at Con Edison... Growing with New York and Westchester" (1962); Article "Con Ed: The Arrogance of Power" by Lucy Komiser (1969); Publication "Statement: Federal Power CommissionHearings, Consolidated Edison at Storm King by the Conservation Center, Inc., New York" (1966); Publication "Natural Beauty Conference: Ulster County Planning Board Summary Report, 1966;" Publication Niagara Mohawk Power Corp. 1966 Annual Report;" Issues of Nuclear Information and Resource Service (NIRS) publication "Nuclear Monitor" (1990) and "Alert" (1991).
    Organizations: Friends of the Hudson; Citizens' Committee for Clean Water; Anti-Pollution League; Safe Energy Alternatives (SEA) Alliance.
    Nuclear Plants: Three Mile Island; Indian Point.
    Other Items: Harrisburg, PA postcard (1980); Program for funeral of Larry Bogart, Sept. 14, 1991, Archer United Methodist Church, Allendale, New Jersey; Correspondence (1965); Citizens' Committee for Clean Water Meeting minutes and agendas (1965); Clippings about Three Mile Island (1980) and Indian Point.
    Other Topics: Effects of Three Mile Island; 1978 Lawsuit agains U.S. NRC by Jeannine Honicker; Planning Nuclear Plants in New York State; Nuclear Power in New Jersey.]
  - Publications, clippings, fliers, dummies, posters, realia, books, 1961, 1964-1965, 1969-1970, 1973, 1976, 1978, 1982, 1984-1987, 1989-1990; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 21)
    Articles and publications: Publication "Federal Register" (1989); United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission "News Announcements" (1985); Publication "People and the Pursuit of Truth" (1976); Article "Initial Effects of the Fallout from the Chernobyl Accident on the U.S. Population" by Dr. E.J. Sternglass (1987); Publication "A Review of Radiological Surveillance Reports of Waste Effluents in Marine Pathways at the Maine Yankee Atomic Power Company at Wiscasset, Maine, 1970-1984" ed. H.G. Brack; Publication "Report of the United Nations Scientific Committee on the Effects of Atomic Radiation" (1964); Article "America's Chernobyls: Forty-Nine U.S. Nuclear Plants Have Containment Systems Similar to Chernobyl's" by Ian Gilbert and Elliott Negin; "Nuclear Hazards" newsletters, publisehd by Citizens Energy Council (1990); Article "Interplanetary Exploration: A Challenge for Photoboltaics" by Paul M. Stella; Flier "Do You Know what Plutonium Is? You'd Better Find Out!;" Publication "Harrowsmith" magazine (1987); Book "A Radiation Monitoring System for Nuclear Power Plants (With Special Reference) to the Three Mile Island Nuclear Power Station" by the Three Mile Island Public Health Fund (December 1987); Article "The Silent Toll Part II: Anatomy of a Cover-Up" by Thomas Pawlick and James Lawrence; Flier "Keowee-Toxaway Visitors Center Presents: The Story of Energy" (undated); Publication "Wisconsin Report" (1982); Publication "Radioactive Waste Campaign: The Report" (1990); Publication "On the Watch" newsletter (1989); Publication "A Strategy for Action" (1970); Publication "Delaware River Basin Compact" (1961); Publication "Before the U.S. Atomic Energy Commission in the Matter of Consolidated Edison Company of New York, INc. (Indian Point Unit No. 3): Summary of Application" (1969); Publication "Nuclear Power Plants" by Ray L. Lyerly and Walter Mitchell, III; Publication "Second Annual Report of the Advisory Council on Environmental Education" (March 1973).
    Organizations: Maryland Safe Energy Coalition; Citizens Energy Council; Union of Concerned Scientists; New England Coalition on Nuclear Pollution, Inc.
    Nuclear Plants: Maine Yankee; Three Mile Island; Indian Point.
    Other Items: Arm bands, reading "TMI Is Not Over" (2); Poster, titled "No Need for Nuclear;" dummies of publication "U.S. Is Vulnerable! Dr. Teller's Warning;" Diagrams of nuclear reactor designs (1965); dummies of untitled Children's book against nuclear power, by Steven Gottlieb (1978).
    Other Topics: Long term effects of Three Mile Island accident; Plutonium aboard Galileo Probe (1989); Nuclear waste disposal.]
  - Clippings, publications, posters, 1968, 1970-1973, 1977, 1979-1981, 1983-1986; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 22)
    Articles and Publications: Publication "Nuclear Energy: A Report of the Committee on Environment of the Saginaw County Medical School" (1971); Publication "Questions and Answers about the Electrical Utility Industry: 1970-1971 Edition" published by Edison Electric Institute; Publication "Draft: Report of the Interagency Task Force on Ionizing Radiation on Institutional Arrangements" (1979); Publication "Photovoltaic Product Directory and Buyers Guide" (1984); Publication "Thinkpeace" newsletter (1986); U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission News Releases (1986); Publications "Nuclear Hazards" (1986) and "Watch on the AEC" (1971-1972), published by the Citizens Energy Council; Publication "Exxon Corp. Annual Report 1984;" Publication "The President's Environmental Program: 1977;" Publication "LIP: The Lancaster Independent Press" (1981); Publication "New York Mobilizer" (1981); Publication "Pennsylvania Power and Light Co. Annual Report 1984;" Publication "Solar Energy Legal Bibliograph Final Report" by Solar Energy Research Institute (1979); Publication "Vermont Yankee Nuclear Power Corporation Financial Statements December 31, 1984, 1983, and 1982;" Article "Our Nuclear Dilemma and the Energy Crisis" by Mildred Kurtz (1973); Publication "SEA Alliance News" (1985); Publication "Safe Energy Communication Council's Myth Busters No. 1" (1986); Article "Labs Drive the Arms Race" by Hugh E. DeWitt (1968); Article "Four Minutes to Midnight" by Nicholas Humphrey (1981); Publication "Environmental News: New Jersey Dpartment of Environmental Protection" (1986); Publication "Disorientation Manual: New Indicator Collective, Universtity of California, San Diego" (1981); Publication "Citizens Energy Project, Report Series No. 110, Four Steps to Oblivion: A Study of Nuclear Proliferation" by Scott Denman; Publication "Nuclear Power: What's at Stake in the Sept. 23 Referendum" (1980).
    Organizations: Citizens Energy Council.
    Nuclear Plants: Vermont Yankee.
    Other Items: Poster for "First Annual Mary Hays Weik Award" (1986).]
  - Publications, manuscripts, fliers, correspondence, maps, clippings, 1957, 1969-1975, 1977, 1979, 1985-1986, 1988, 1990; 1.3 Linear feet Foldered (Box 23)